<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Samrose Ahmed</title>
    <link>https://samrose.dev/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Samrose Ahmed</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:14:36 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://samrose.dev/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Say to my friends when they see me dead (قل لإخوان رأوني ميتا)</title>
      <link>https://samrose.dev/posts/say_to_my_friends/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2019 00:14:36 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://samrose.dev/posts/say_to_my_friends/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Imam Al Ghazzali woke up one early morning and as usual offered his prayers. He then enquired what day it was and his younger brother, Ahmad Ghazzali replied, &amp;ldquo;Monday&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He asked him to bring his white shroud, kissed it, stretched himself full length and saying “Lord, I obey willingly,” breathed his last.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Underneath his head rest they found the following verses; composed by him, probably, during the night:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Say to my friends, when they look upon me, dead,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Weeping for me and mourning me in sorrow,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;‘Do not believe that this corpse you see is myself,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the name of God, I tell you, it is not I,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a spirit, and this is naught but flesh,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was my abode and my garment for a time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a treasure, by a talisman kept hid,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fashioned of dust, which served me as a shrine,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a pearl, which has left it’s shell deserted,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am a bird, and this body was my cage,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whence I have now flown forth and it is left as a token,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Praise to God, who hath now set me free,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And prepared for me my place in the highest of the Heavens,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Until today I was dead, though alive in your midst.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now I live in truth, with the grave – clothes discarded.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Today I hold converse with the Saints above,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With no veil between, I see God face to face.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I look upon “Loh-i-Mahfuz” and there in I read,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whatever was and is, and all that is to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let my house fall in ruins, lay my cage in the ground,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cast away the talisman, it is a token no more,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lay aside my cloak, it was but my outer garment.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Place them all in the grave, let them be forgotten,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have passed on my way and you are left behind,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your place of abode was no dwelling place for me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think not that death is death, nay, it is life,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A life that surpasses all we could dream of here,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While in this world, here we are granted sleep,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death is but sleep, sleep that shall be prolonged&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Be not frightened when death draweth nigh,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is but the departure for this blessed home,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Think of the mercy and love of your Lord,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Give thanks for His Grace and come without fear.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am now, even so shall you be,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For I know that you are even as I am,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The souls of all men come forth from God,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The bodies of all are compounded alike,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good and evil, alike it was ours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I give you now a message of good cheer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;May God’s peace and joy forever more be yours.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>